[('Secretary', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('State', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('P.', 'PERSON'), ('Shultz', 'PERSON'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('relented', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('agreed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('conditions', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('envoy', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('discuss', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('servicemen', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Shultz', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('speaking', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('annual', 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('League', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Families', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Prisoners', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Missing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Southeast', 'LOCATION'), ('Asia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('warned', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('progress', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('no', 'O'), ('longer', 'O'), ('insisted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('discussions', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('servicemen', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('linked', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('normalizing', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''We", 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('pleased', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Vietnamese', 'O'), ('Government', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('accepted', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('proposal', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('visit', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Presidential', 'O'), ('emissary', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('P.O.W', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('M.I.A', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('humanitarian', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''We", 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('pleased', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Hanoi', 'LOCATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('sides', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('link', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('humanitarian', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('outstanding', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('countries', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Earlier', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('month', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Vietnamese', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Hanoi', 'LOCATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('negotiators', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('letter', 'O'), ('dropping', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('previous', 'O'), ('conditions', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('talks', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Shultz', 'PERSON'), ('warned', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('might', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('try', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('economic', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('exchange', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('genuine', 'O'), ('discussion', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('servicemen', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''We", 'O'), ('intend', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('honor', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('agreement', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('expect', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('understanding', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('normalization', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('included', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('discussions', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''Nevertheless", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('spite', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('agreements', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('possibility', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('able', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('move', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('forward', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Disturbed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Press', 'O'), ('Reports', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('disturbed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('despite', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('agreement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('might', 'O'), ('try', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('raise', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('reparations', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('economic', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('heading', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('humanitarian', 'O'), ('cooperation', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''Humanitarian", 'O'), ('reciprocity', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('thing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('attempt', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('trade', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('economic', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''We", 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('agree', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('An', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('negotiating', 'O'), ('team', 'O'), ('returned', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Hanoi', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('May', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('failing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('persuade', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('accept', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('visit', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('presidential', 'O'), ('envoy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Gen.', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('A.', 'PERSON'), ('Vessey', 'PERSON'), ('Jr.', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('retired', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Joint', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chiefs', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Staff', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O'), ("''The", 'O'), ('Government', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('agreed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('receive', 'O'), ('General', 'O'), ('Vessey', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('discuss', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hanoi', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Shultz', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''We", 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('working', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('final', 'O'), ('details', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Vietnamese', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('No', 'O'), ('date', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Vessey', 'PERSON'), ('mission', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Foreign', 'O'), ('Minister', 'O'), ('Interviewed', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('remark', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('apparently', 'O'), ('refers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Vietnamese', 'O'), ('Foreign', 'O'), ('Minister', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Nguyen', 'PERSON'), ('Co', 'PERSON'), ('Thach', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Washington', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('this', 'O'), ('month', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Hanoi', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Thach', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('intended', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('raise', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('variety', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('category', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('humanitarian', 'O'), ('matters', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('personal', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'O'), ('War', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''If", 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('M.I.A', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('heal', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('wounds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('war', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('seeking', 'O'), ('Vietnamese', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('determining', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fate', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('2,500', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('servicemen', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('failed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('return', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('prisoner-of-war', 'O'), ('camps', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Hanoi', 'LOCATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('stalling', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('agreeing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('hopes', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('would', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('allow', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('discussions', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('normalization', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Vietnamese', 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('normalization', 'O'), ('discussions', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('reparations', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('Administration', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('adamant', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('talks', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('servicemen', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('precede', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('discussion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('improving', 'O'), ('diplomatic', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('Senator', 'O'), ('Claiborne', 'PERSON'), ('Pell', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Democrat', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Rhode', 'LOCATION'), ('Island', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Foreign', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Relations', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('suggested', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Administration', 'O'), ('proceed', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('normalizing', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Hanoi', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O'), ('LANGUAGE', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('ENGLISH', 'O'), ('GRAPHIC', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Photo', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Sec', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('State', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('P.', 'PERSON'), ('Shultz', 'PERSON'), ('after', 'O'), ('addressing', 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('League', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Families', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Prisoners', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Missing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Southeast', 'LOCATION'), ('Asia', 'LOCATION'), ('(', 'O'), ('NYTMarty', 'O'), ('Katz', 'PERSON'), (')', 'O')]